CURRICULUM VITAE



PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : Dr. Mohd Anis bin Haron @ Harun

Date of Birth 6 January 1965 Age : 48+ years Sex Male

Date of Enlistment : 12 August 1991 Nationality : Malaysian Marital Status : Married

No. of Dependence : 7 (Wife, 4 Children and Parents)

Medical Status : FE (Fit Everywhere) : 10, Jalan Desaria 13 Correspondence Address Taman Desaria

71800 Nilai

Negeri Sembilan

Tel. No. : +603-83124355 (office)

+60133841078 (mobile)

E-mail ppanish@hpj.gov.my

anis_64@yahoo.com

Language

Proficiency Fluent Good 1. Bahasa Malaysia Good

English Fluent 2.

SPOKEN

WRITTEN

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Medical Degree (MD), National University of Malaysia (UKM), 1991

- Masters in Public Health (Health Management), National University of Malaysia (UKM), 2000
- Certified Medical Impairment Assessor (CMIA), National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health Malaysia (NIOSH), 2006
- Certified Lead Auditor for MS ISO 9001:2008

PRESENT APPOINTMENT (2004-Present)

- Deputy Director (Hospital)
- Hospital Putrajaya

PREVIO	ous A	APPO	INTM	ENTS
--------	-------	-------------	------	------

Principal Assistant Director Grade UD 54 Private Medical Practice Control Section

Medical Practice Division, Ministry of Health, Malaysia

2000-2004 : Assistant Director

Licensing Unit, Medical Practice Division

Ministry of Health Malaysia

1994-1998 : Medical Officer

Students Health Centre

National University of Malaysia (UKM)

1993-1994 : Medical Officer

Kajang Hospital, Selangor

1992-1993 : Medical Officer

Health Clinic

Tatau, Bintulu, Sarawak

1991-1992 : Houseman

Sarawak General Hospital

Kuching, Sarawak

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2012 : • Attended Oxford Programme on Negotiation (23-28/09/2012)

Said Business School, University of Oxford, United Kingdom

Presenter at "Patient Flow Optimization Asia 2012 Conference"
"Hospital Putrajaya: Leveraging Total Hospital Information System (THIS) to Improve Patient Flow and Reduce Patient Wait Time"

2010 : • Attachment (10-21 Octob

Attachment (10-21 October 2010) at the Licensing Standard and Review Unit (LSRU) of the Department of Health, Western Australia

Main Secretariat

- Main Committee on Amendment of the Thirteenth Schedule
- Task Force for Amendment of the Thirteenth Schedule
- Main Secretariat

Appointment and Implementation of Board of Visitors for Private Hospitals

Co-Author

Guidelines on the Appointment and Role of Board of Visitors for Private Hospitals

Main Secretariat

Incident Reporting and Notification of Assessable Death

- Core team in the implementation of Mental Health Act 2001 and Mental Health Regulations 2010
- Co-Author

Manuals and Forms for Incident Reporting and Notification of Assessable Death

Co-Author for Medical Practice Division

10th Malaysia Plan

2009-2010 : • Lecturer

"Private Healthcare Facilities and Services Act 1998 and its

Regulations", Diploma in Family Medicine (DFM) Workshop

Main Secretariat and Drafter

Committee on Amendment to the Private Healthcare Facilities and

Services Regulations

2008-2010 : Committee Member and Co-Drafter

Amendment to the Fees (Medical) Order, 1982

2007-2010 : Chairperson

SOCSO Appellate Board

2005-2010 : Lead/Internal Auditor for ISO Certification

2004-2010 Core team in the development and upgrading of the Medical Practice

Control System (MedPCs) from on-line registration and licensing of the private healthcare facilities and services to incident reporting, notification of assessable death and nomination of members of the Board of Visitors

for private hospitals

2006-2009 Chairperson

Subcommittee on Review of Floor Plan for Private Healthcare Facilities

and Services

2008 : Teaching

> "Private Healthcare Facilities and Services Act 1998 and its Regulations" Training for Auditor for Malaysian Society of Quality in Health (MSQH)

2007-2008 : Core team in the development of e-reporting for in patients, day care

patients and health tourism patients for compulsory submission of

statistical information to the Ministry of Health

2006-2008 : Committee Member and Drafter

Fees (Medical) (Full Paying Patient) Order 2008

2003-2006 : Main Secretariat

Finalising of the Private Healthcare Facilities and Services Regulations

2006 for both clinics and other private healthcare facilities and services

: Representative of Ministry of Health and Presenter 2001-2004

Trade Mission for the Promotion of Health Tourism in Malaysia in Dubai,

Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, Myanmar, Vietnam and Indonesia

2000-2001 : Main Secretariat

Mental Health Act 2001

PROFILE STATEMENT

Field of Expertise Public health specialist (Management)

Regulating private healthcare facilities and services

Consultant for establishment and operation of private healthcare

facilities and services

Regulating fees related to private healthcare facilities and services

Handling grievances and matters relating to enforcement

Consultant for matters relating to incident reporting, notification of assessable deaths, Board of Visitors, Board of Management and Medical (and Dental) Advisory Committee

Development of health-related legislations

Work Ethics,

A fully committed professional team player.

A trouble shooter and problem solver

Good interpersonal skills and networking

Able to work under pressure, travel when necessary and work at flexible hours as and when required

Always thriving to excel in all undertakings

Strength and

Versatility

PUBLICATIONS

2011 : Annual Report on Medical Practice Division, Ministry of Health, 2010 2010 : Annual Report on Private Medical Practice Section, Ministry of Health,

2008 : Co-Author, Director General Report on the Private Healthcare Facilities

and Services Act 1998 and its Implementation

2005 Co-Author, Director General Report on Health Tourism in Malaysia

SCIENTIFIC PRESENTATIONS

2008 : Presenter

"The Implication of Private Healthcare Facilities and Services Act 1998

[Act 586] on the Future of Private Psychiatry Practice and Services"

2008 Private Psychiatry Chapter Conference

2007 : Presenter

"Quality Through Legislation"